

Baikov Alexey

35 years, Nizhny Novgorod

Python developer / Backend developer

Level: Junior, Junior+, Middle-Employment: full time, part time,

Work schedule: remote working, full day

Contacts

- +7 (929) 053-73-35
- https://t.me/alexbaikov
- alex@baikov.dev
- https://baikov.dev
- https://github.com/baikov

About

More than 10 years of experience in website development and SEO helped me to acquire skills from every point of Full-stack development. I hope that the new stack and deepening in the backend will allow me to participate in the development of larger and more interesting projects. My goals for this year: to become a Middle+ Python developer and raise my English level to B2.

Work Experience

Learning new stack

I applied all the studied technologies in practice (project allflags.ru)

A short list of practical skills:

- · VPS administration, work with Heroku, AWS, Yandex.Cloud;
- · Configuring Nginx, Traefik, Prometheus, Grafana;
- Working with Docker and Docker Compose, basics of CI/CD;
- · Codestyle (flake8, black), testing (pytest, coverage), documenting (Sphinx);
- · Working with version control and workflows (git, github, git-flow, github-flow);
- Working with Django, DRF, PostgreSQL, Redis, Celery, Flower.

 Python
 Dijango
 Git
 Docker
 Celery
 PostgreSQL
 DRF
 Redis
 CI/CD
 Traefik
 Linux

PKF Luidor, Nizhny Novgorod (Car factory / special vehicles)

Web developer, SEO specialist

- Developed a service for finding spare parts by VIN (backend: Django/DRF, frontend: Vue.js);
- Development and SEO of the company's websites on 1C-Bitrix;
- · More than 3 years of experience in remote work.

Freelance, own projects

Full-stack developer, SEO specialist

- · Website development and SEO (Joomla, WordPress, 1C-Bitrix, OpenCart).
- ⇒ september 2011 april 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Redox, Moscow (commerce / health products)

Product Manager

Redox, Nizhny Novgorod (retail / health products)

Sales Manager

i movember 2006 − may 2008 (1 year 7 months)

Telma Soft, Nizhny Novgorod (software development)

Trainee engineer in the software development and testing department

· Internship while studying at the university

Education

LOBACHEVSKY SUNN

Lobachevsky State University of Nizhny Novgorod

a 2004-2009 (5 years), full time, specialist

Faculty of Computational
Mathematics and Cybernetics
Specialty: Applied Mathematics
and Informatics

Qualification: mathematician, system programmer

Languages

Russian Native
English Intermediate

Courses

Docker

2021. slurm.io

Build a Backend REST API with Python & Django

2021, Udemi

Algorithms and Data Structures in Python 3

2021, YouTube

l Projects

Country flags

baikov/allflags

Search parts by VIN

f https://parts.baikov.dev

baikov/autoparts

Books

Python Tricks, Dan Bader
Grokking Algorithms, Aditya Bhargava
Practices of the Python Pro, Dane Hillard
Django 3.0. The practice of developing
websites in python, Dronov V. A.